<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Morten Dæhli Aslesen</title><link>https://mortendaehli.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Morten Dæhli Aslesen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Morten Dæhli Aslesen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 20:10:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mortendaehli.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to get started with your personal Hugo blog on GitHub Pages</title><link>https://mortendaehli.github.io/project/2021-12-11-create-personal-hugo-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 20:10:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mortendaehli.github.io/project/2021-12-11-create-personal-hugo-blog/</guid><description>Introduction This is a guide to create your own static Hugo blog platform. It will deploy automatically using GitHub Actions and be hosted on GitHub Pages. With one simple command you can also refer it to your own custom domain using a Canonical Name record (CNAME).
Follow along and replace my username &amp;ldquo;mortendaehli&amp;rdquo; with your username, and my domain www.daehli.no with your domain if you chose to use your own custom domain.</description></item><item><title>My Readling List</title><link>https://mortendaehli.github.io/project/2021-12-11-my-readling-list/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 19:03:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mortendaehli.github.io/project/2021-12-11-my-readling-list/</guid><description>Introduction This is a curated list of reading material and code projects that I enjoy and recommend to others:
Reading Coding Architecture Patterns with Python by Harry Percival, Bob Gregory Test-Driven Web Development with Python by Harry Percival Python: Functional programming HOWTO by A. M. Kuchling General tech Stop Emailing Like A Rube - Jeffery Paul Projects General Advent of Code Web HUGO - The world’s fastest framework for building websites Machine learning Explainable AI with Shap - Scott Lundberg Forecasting at scale with Facebook Prophet</description></item><item><title>Advent of Code 2021</title><link>https://mortendaehli.github.io/project/2021-12-11-advent-of-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 18:06:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mortendaehli.github.io/project/2021-12-11-advent-of-code/</guid><description>About project This is an effort to solve Advent of Code 2021 if I get the time! You will find my code adventure at GitHub Advent of Code 2021
Install I am solving this using mostly python 3.9, but in order to build a proper environment you need to install Poetry and run
git clone git@github.com:mortendaehli/advent-of-code-2021.git cd advent-of-code-2021 poetry install Then you can explore each day in each sub-folder under advent_of_code_2021.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://mortendaehli.github.io/page/contact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 18:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mortendaehli.github.io/page/contact/</guid><description>Contact You can reach me at post@deahli.no, LinkedIn and Facebook.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://mortendaehli.github.io/page/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 17:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mortendaehli.github.io/page/about/</guid><description>This is me 👋 Hi, I’m Morten Dæhli Aslesen, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently working as an IT-consultant at Bouvet Norway ASA where I&amp;rsquo;ve been since 2020. My background is in Economics and Nanotechnology, but my professional career has been focused on advanced data analytics.
My primary focus at the moment is building cloud-based data platforms. I&amp;rsquo;m an avid DevOps practitioner - to be honest, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like to just automate all the boring stuff and make sure it just works?</description></item><item><title>A complete Step-by-Step Google Search engine optimization guide</title><link>https://mortendaehli.github.io/2021/03/13/2021-03-13-search-engine-optimization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mortendaehli.github.io/2021/03/13/2021-03-13-search-engine-optimization/</guid><description>Search engine optimization (SEO) is the process of increasing the quality and quantity of traffic stemming from search engines. The goal is to increase unpaid, so-called organic, traffic by ranking high on search engines. This is the holy grail of Internet marketing.
I&amp;rsquo;m writing this guide because I&amp;rsquo;m currently helping out my family&amp;rsquo;s business over at Min Symaskin. The name translates to &amp;ldquo;My sewing machine&amp;rdquo;, and we are in the business of selling sewing machines.</description></item><item><title>Create a Ghost Blog on Azure Web Apps Using Docker</title><link>https://mortendaehli.github.io/2021/03/10/2021-03-11-create-a-ghost-blog-on-azure-web-apps-using-docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 18:10:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mortendaehli.github.io/2021/03/10/2021-03-11-create-a-ghost-blog-on-azure-web-apps-using-docker/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered how you can host your tech-blog? If you are like me, and you&amp;rsquo;ve built countless prototypes from scratch. They all work and do what they are meant to do. But something is off. They just don&amp;rsquo;t look any good, and they are not that user-friendly. I recently came across a solution, inspired by a fellow Bouvet colleague, I&amp;rsquo;m now running my very own blog in the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Forecasting Covid-19 vaccinations in Norway</title><link>https://mortendaehli.github.io/2021/03/10/2021-03-11-forecasting-covid-19-vaccnations-in-norway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 18:10:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mortendaehli.github.io/2021/03/10/2021-03-11-forecasting-covid-19-vaccnations-in-norway/</guid><description>In this blog post, we will try to predict the Covid-19 vaccination race in Norway. Most of us are looking forward to getting &amp;ldquo;back to normal&amp;rdquo; - and vaccination is probably the only realistic solution.
The question we are trying to answer is - how are the outlooks towards summer 2021? I feel that the Norwegian government is pretty optimistic when it comes to vaccination rates. Below is a facsimile from the Norwegian national newspaper VG visualizing prognosis data from the Norwegian Institute of Public Health.</description></item><item><title>Creating a New Theme</title><link>https://mortendaehli.github.io/2014/09/28/creating-a-new-theme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mortendaehli.github.io/2014/09/28/creating-a-new-theme/</guid><description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description></item><item><title>Migrating from Jekyll</title><link>https://mortendaehli.github.io/2014/04/02/migrate-from-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mortendaehli.github.io/2014/04/02/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid><description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description></item></channel></rss>