<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Morten Dæhli Aslesen</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/</link><description>Recent content on Morten Dæhli Aslesen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Morten Dæhli Aslesen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 11:37:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.daehli.no/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What I talk about when I talk about coding</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2022/08/07/2022-08-07-what-i-talk-about-when-talk-about-coding/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 11:37:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2022/08/07/2022-08-07-what-i-talk-about-when-talk-about-coding/</guid><description>The fundamental idea of programming computers is to convey an idea. The idea is communicated to both machines and humans, and is brought to life when code is executed by a machine. To bring such an idea to life you need to follow certain rules. Most programmers are able to conform to these rules using a modern IDE and documentation.
This is where everything starts to get complicated. Should you do imperative og declarative programming?</description></item><item><title>Reading list</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/page/reading-list/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/page/reading-list/</guid><description>This is a curated list of reading material and code projects that I enjoy and recommend to others:
Coding philosophy Twelve-factor app Architecture Patterns with Python by Harry Percival, Bob Gregory Test-Driven Web Development with Python by Harry Percival Python: Functional programming HOWTO by A. M. Kuchling Awesome scalability An updated and organized reading list for illustrating the patterns of scalable, reliable, and performant large-scale systems. The C4 model for visualising software architecture - Context, Containers, Components, and Code General tech Stop Emailing Like A Rube - Jeffery Paul Security Cybersecurity readings Projects General Advent of Code Web HUGO - The world’s fastest framework for building websites Streamlit - A faster way to build and share data apps Machine learning Explainable AI with Shap - Scott Lundberg Forecasting at scale with Facebook Prophet Featuretools Featuretools is a python library for automated feature engineering.</description></item><item><title>Event-driven backtesting</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/project/2021-12-11-event-driven-backtesting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 22:20:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/project/2021-12-11-event-driven-backtesting/</guid><description>Introduction This is a proper platform for backtesting financial trading strategies such as stocks, derivatives, and more. The project is built with extensibility in mind, and it is relatively robust and easy to understand.
The project is located at https://github.com/mortendaehli/backtester
Development Setup More to come!</description></item><item><title>SQL Injections</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/project/2021-12-11-sql-injections/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 22:08:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/project/2021-12-11-sql-injections/</guid><description>Introduction This is a work-in-progress code for scanning and injecting SQL commands. The code was initially created in order to test SQL injections for OWASP Juice Shop
The project is located at https://github.com/mortendaehli/owasp-sql-injections
Development Setup I am solving this using mostly python 3.9, but in order to build a proper environment you need to install Poetry and run
git git@github.com:mortendaehli/owasp-sql-injections.git cd owasp-sql-injections poetry install Host OWASP Juice Shop for testing Using Docker we can spin up an instance of the Juice Shop:</description></item><item><title>HUGO</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/project/2021-12-11-create-personal-hugo-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 20:10:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/project/2021-12-11-create-personal-hugo-blog/</guid><description>Introduction This is a guide to create your own static Hugo blog platform. It will deploy automatically using GitHub Actions and be hosted on GitHub Pages. With one simple command you can also refer it to your own custom domain using a Canonical Name record (CNAME).
Follow along and replace my username &amp;ldquo;mortendaehli&amp;rdquo; with your username, and my domain www.daehli.no with your domain if you chose to use your own custom domain.</description></item><item><title>Advent of Code 2021</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/project/2021-12-11-advent-of-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 18:06:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/project/2021-12-11-advent-of-code/</guid><description>Introduction This is an effort to solve Advent of Code 2021 if I get the time! You will find my code adventure at GitHub Advent of Code 2021
Development Setup I am solving this using mostly python 3.9, but in order to build a proper environment you need to install Poetry and run
git clone git@github.com:mortendaehli/advent-of-code-2021.git cd advent-of-code-2021 poetry install Then you can explore each day in each sub-folder under advent_of_code_2021.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/page/contact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 18:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/page/contact/</guid><description>Contact You can reach me at:
Gmail LinkedIn GitHub Facebook</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/page/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 17:37:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/page/about/</guid><description>This is me 👋 Hi, I’m Morten Dæhli Aslesen, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently working as an IT-consultant at Bouvet Norway ASA where I&amp;rsquo;ve been since 2020. My background is in Economics and Nanotechnology, but in my professional career I have been focusing on advanced analytics, machine learning, data platforms and software development.
I&amp;rsquo;m an avid DevOps practitioner, I prefer simple elegant and pragmatic solutions, clean explicit code and trunk based development.</description></item><item><title>A complete Step-by-Step Google Search engine optimization guide</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2021/03/13/2021-03-13-search-engine-optimization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2021/03/13/2021-03-13-search-engine-optimization/</guid><description>Search engine optimization (SEO) is the process of increasing the quality and quantity of traffic stemming from search engines. The goal is to increase unpaid, so-called organic, traffic by ranking high on search engines. This is the holy grail of Internet marketing.
I&amp;rsquo;m writing this guide because I&amp;rsquo;m currently helping out my family&amp;rsquo;s business over at Min Symaskin. The name translates to &amp;ldquo;My sewing machine&amp;rdquo;, and we are in the business of selling sewing machines.</description></item><item><title>Create a Ghost Blog using Azure Web Apps</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/project/2021-03-11-create-a-ghost-blog-on-azure-web-apps-using-docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 18:10:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/project/2021-03-11-create-a-ghost-blog-on-azure-web-apps-using-docker/</guid><description>⚠️ This guide is outdated: Azure store account does not support this service anymore! So I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to HUGO using GitHub Pages. An easy to follow guide can be found in HUGO&amp;rsquo;s own Host on GitHub docs.
Have you ever wondered how you can host your own tech-blog? If you are like me, and you&amp;rsquo;ve built countless prototypes from scratch. They all work and do what they are meant to do.</description></item><item><title>Forecasting Covid-19 vaccinations in Norway</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2021/03/10/2021-03-11-forecasting-covid-19-vaccnations-in-norway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 18:10:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2021/03/10/2021-03-11-forecasting-covid-19-vaccnations-in-norway/</guid><description>In this blog post, we will try to predict the Covid-19 vaccination race in Norway. We are all looking forward to getting &amp;ldquo;back to normal&amp;rdquo; - and wide vaccination coverage is probably the only realistic way to get there.
The question we are trying to answer is - how is the vaccine coverage going to be during the summer of 2021? I feel that the Norwegian government is pretty optimistic when it comes to vaccination rates.</description></item></channel></rss>