<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Morten Dæhli Aslesen</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Morten Dæhli Aslesen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Morten Dæhli Aslesen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 11:37:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.daehli.no/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What I think about when I talk about coding</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2022/08/07/2022-08-07-what-i-think-about-when-talk-about-coding/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 11:37:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2022/08/07/2022-08-07-what-i-think-about-when-talk-about-coding/</guid><description>The fundamental idea of programming computers is to convey an idea. The idea is communicated to both machines and humans, and is brought to life when code is executed by a machine. To bring such an idea to life you need to follow certain rules. Most programmers are able to conform to these rules using a modern IDE and documentation.
This is where everything starts to get complicated. Should you do imperative og declarative programming?</description></item><item><title>A complete Step-by-Step Google Search engine optimization guide</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2021/03/13/2021-03-13-search-engine-optimization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2021/03/13/2021-03-13-search-engine-optimization/</guid><description>Search engine optimization (SEO) is the process of increasing the quality and quantity of traffic stemming from search engines. The goal is to increase unpaid, so-called organic, traffic by ranking high on search engines. This is the holy grail of Internet marketing.
I&amp;rsquo;m writing this guide because I&amp;rsquo;m currently helping out my family&amp;rsquo;s business over at Min Symaskin. The name translates to &amp;ldquo;My sewing machine&amp;rdquo;, and we are in the business of selling sewing machines.</description></item><item><title>Forecasting Covid-19 vaccinations in Norway</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2021/03/10/2021-03-11-forecasting-covid-19-vaccnations-in-norway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 18:10:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2021/03/10/2021-03-11-forecasting-covid-19-vaccnations-in-norway/</guid><description>In this blog post, we will try to predict the Covid-19 vaccination race in Norway. We are all looking forward to getting &amp;ldquo;back to normal&amp;rdquo; - and wide vaccination coverage is probably the only realistic way to get there.
The question we are trying to answer is - how is the vaccine coverage going to be during the summer of 2021? I feel that the Norwegian government is pretty optimistic when it comes to vaccination rates.</description></item></channel></rss>