<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Morten Dæhli Aslesen</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Morten Dæhli Aslesen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Morten Dæhli Aslesen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 12:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.daehli.no/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Object oriented design patterns - Structural patterns (Part 2)</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2023/04/10/2023-04-10-structural-design-patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2023/04/10/2023-04-10-structural-design-patterns/</guid><description>This is the second part in a series of 3 blog post summarizing the famous by Gamma, Helm, Johnson and Vlissides, also known as the Gang of Four.
See the first post for an overview:
Creational Patters - Part 1 Structural Patterns Structural patterns are design patterns that deal with object composition to form larger structures, such as class and object relationships, to simplify the design and implementation of complex systems.</description></item><item><title>Object oriented design patterns - Creational patterns (Part 1)</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2023/04/09/2023-04-09-creational-design-patterns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 10:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2023/04/09/2023-04-09-creational-design-patterns/</guid><description>This is the first part in a series of 3 blog post summarizing the classic book &amp;ldquo;Design Patterns: Elements of Reusable Object-Oriented Software&amp;rdquo; by Gamma, Helm, Johnson and Vlissides, collectively known as the Gang of Four (GoF). The book is widely regarded as a seminal work in the field of software engineering and is frequently cited as one of the most influential books in the industry.
The book focuses on the concept of software design patterns, which are reusable solutions to common programming problems.</description></item><item><title>This is how you get a clean git history</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2022/10/31/2022-10-31-clean-git-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 16:58:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2022/10/31/2022-10-31-clean-git-history/</guid><description>Communication is a core pillar when it comes to working as a team. Without good communication it is almost impossible for a team to achieve great things. As developers, we are lucky to have many tools helping us to become great communicators and good team players. One of those tools are git. It&amp;rsquo;s infamous for being counter-intuitive and easy to screw up. It&amp;rsquo;s quite fitting that Oh Shit, Git!?! has helped many developers in dire need of git guidance.</description></item><item><title>What I talk about when I talk about coding</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2022/08/07/2022-08-07-what-i-talk-about-when-talk-about-coding/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 11:37:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2022/08/07/2022-08-07-what-i-talk-about-when-talk-about-coding/</guid><description>The fundamental idea of programming computers is to convey an idea. The idea is communicated to both machines and humans, and is brought to life when code is executed by a machine. To bring such an idea to life you need to follow certain rules. Most programmers are able to conform to these rules using a modern IDE and documentation.
This is where everything starts to get complicated. Should you do imperative og declarative programming?</description></item><item><title>A complete Step-by-Step Google Search engine optimization guide</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2021/03/13/2021-03-13-search-engine-optimization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2021/03/13/2021-03-13-search-engine-optimization/</guid><description>Search engine optimization (SEO) is the process of increasing the quality and quantity of traffic stemming from search engines. The goal is to increase unpaid, so-called organic, traffic by ranking high on search engines. This is the holy grail of Internet marketing.
I&amp;rsquo;m writing this guide because I&amp;rsquo;m currently helping out my family&amp;rsquo;s business over at Min Symaskin. The name translates to &amp;ldquo;My sewing machine&amp;rdquo;, and we are in the business of selling sewing machines.</description></item><item><title>Forecasting Covid-19 vaccinations in Norway</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2021/03/10/2021-03-11-forecasting-covid-19-vaccnations-in-norway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 18:10:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2021/03/10/2021-03-11-forecasting-covid-19-vaccnations-in-norway/</guid><description>In this blog post, we will try to predict the Covid-19 vaccination race in Norway. We are all looking forward to getting &amp;ldquo;back to normal&amp;rdquo; - and wide vaccination coverage is probably the only realistic way to get there.
The question we are trying to answer is - how is the vaccine coverage going to be during the summer of 2021? I feel that the Norwegian government is pretty optimistic when it comes to vaccination rates.</description></item></channel></rss>