<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>software design on Morten Dæhli Aslesen</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/tags/software-design/</link><description>Recent content in software design on Morten Dæhli Aslesen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Morten Dæhli Aslesen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 12:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.daehli.no/tags/software-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Object oriented design patterns - Structural patterns (Part 2)</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2023/04/10/2023-04-10-structural-design-patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2023/04/10/2023-04-10-structural-design-patterns/</guid><description>This is the second part in a series of 3 blog post summarizing the famous by Gamma, Helm, Johnson and Vlissides, also known as the Gang of Four.
See the first post for an overview:
Creational Patters - Part 1 Structural Patterns Structural patterns are design patterns that deal with object composition to form larger structures, such as class and object relationships, to simplify the design and implementation of complex systems.</description></item><item><title>Object oriented design patterns - Creational patterns (Part 1)</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/2023/04/09/2023-04-09-creational-design-patterns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 10:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/2023/04/09/2023-04-09-creational-design-patterns/</guid><description>This is the first part in a series of 3 blog post summarizing the classic book &amp;ldquo;Design Patterns: Elements of Reusable Object-Oriented Software&amp;rdquo; by Gamma, Helm, Johnson and Vlissides, collectively known as the Gang of Four (GoF). The book is widely regarded as a seminal work in the field of software engineering and is frequently cited as one of the most influential books in the industry.
The book focuses on the concept of software design patterns, which are reusable solutions to common programming problems.</description></item></channel></rss>