<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Morten Dæhli Aslesen</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Morten Dæhli Aslesen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Morten Dæhli Aslesen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 11:33:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.daehli.no/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reading list</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/page/reading-list/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/page/reading-list/</guid><description>Welcome to my treasure trove of resources! In this curated list, I share the reading materials and code projects that have not only enriched my understanding but also shaped my approach in the tech world. Each item here is more than just a recommendation — it&amp;rsquo;s a reflection of the philosophies and practices I believe in.
Coding philosophy Twelve-factor app Architecture Patterns with Python by Harry Percival, Bob Gregory Test-Driven Web Development with Python by Harry Percival Python: Functional programming HOWTO by A.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/page/contact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 18:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/page/contact/</guid><description>Contact You can reach me at:
Gmail LinkedIn GitHub Facebook</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://www.daehli.no/page/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 17:37:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.daehli.no/page/about/</guid><description>This is me 👋 Hi, I’m Morten Dæhli Aslesen, an IT-consultant at Bouvet Norway ASA since 2020. My academical background is in Economics and Nanotechnology, but in my professional career I have been focusing on advanced analytics, machine learning, data platforms and software development.
I&amp;rsquo;m an avid DevOps practitioner, my mantra is simplicity, elegance, and pragmatism. I strive for clean, explicit code and champion trunk-based development.. In my spare time, I&amp;rsquo;m always working on something new.</description></item></channel></rss>